HIKKADUWA LIYANAGE PASINDU MALSHAN

205/4, Kelamadeniya, Gelioya, Sri Lanka hlpmalshan@gmail.com \diamond +94 77 843 1832

SUMMARY

I am a student studying electrical and electronic engineering who loves learning and figuring out how things work. I enjoy working on real projects and have experience with both software and hardware solutions. I am not only passionate about learning but also about sharing what I know with others. Over the years, I have gained experience in imparting knowledge to my peers. I believe in the importance of spreading information and helping others understand complex concepts. Whether it is through group projects or informal discussions, I take joy in sharing what I have learned to contribute to a collaborative and supportive learning environment. As I have gone through school and university, I have learned how to communicate well, manage my time, and take the lead in projects. I can take on responsibilities and work with little supervision.

INTERESTS

Optimization Machine Learning Signal Processing Algorithmic Programming

EDUCATION

University of Peradeniya 2018 Nov - Present

Undergraduate in BSc. Engineering(Hons.) GPA: 3.81/4.00

DeepLearning.AI and Stanford University 2023

Coursera Online Certificate Courses

Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Kingswood College ,Kandy 2008 - 2016

G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination

District Rank - 17, Island Rank - 253 Z-Score: 2.1336

Physics (A), Chemistry (A), Combined Mathematics (A)

G.C.E. Ordinary Level Examination

A passes for all 9 subjects

Sri Pada College, Hatton 2003 - 2007

2023

ACHIEVEMENTS

Undergrad Thesis Project Competition

Organized by IEEE Signal Processing Society Sri Lanka Chapter

Runners Up

SKILLS

Programming Languages Java, Python

Numerical Computing Packages MATLAB, Octave, Numpy, R

Hardware Programming Arduino
3D Modelling AutoCAD

Design and Multimedia Tools Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Illustrator

Office Productivity Suite Microsoft Office Package

English Sinhelese

Languages English, Sinhalese

EXPERIENCE

Past Paper TV: Educational YouTube Channel

2021 - Present

Educational YouTube channel for GCE A/L Students which provides theory and past paper discussions Has over 49K subscriber count

GCE A/L Tutoring

2018 - Present

Conducting individual tutoring sessions on Combined Mathematics for numerous advanced-level students

Pearson Edexcel A/L and O/L Tutoring

2018 - Present

Conducting individual tutoring sessions on Pure Mathematics, Further Mathematics, Mechanics, and Statistics for numerous advanced-level and ordinary-level students

Sri Lanka Telecom PLC - Trainee Engineer

2022 January - 2022 May

Involved in projects and garnered practical experience in the areas of Fiber Access Network, Copper Access Network

PROJECTS

Multispectral Imaging for Condition Monitoring

2023

- · Developed a method to monitor the changes in different substances from multispectral imaging
- · Technologies: Python, Numpy, OpenCV
- Techniques: Image Preprocessing (Median Filtering, Bilateral Filtering), Dimension Reduction (PCA, LDA), Data Classification (Logistic Regression, SVM, Decision Tree, KNN), Statistical Parameters (Bhattacharyya Distance, KL Divergence)

2022 Smart Key Chain

- · Designed and manufactured a comprehensive smart key chain solution for locating misplaced objects
- · Technologies: Arduino Microcontroller, ESP8266 Wifi Module, Android Studio

High Speed Traffic Indicator

2022

- · Designed and simulated a high speed traffic indicator which can identify vehicles speed and indicate warnings
- Technologies: PIC 16F877A Microcontroller, IR Sensors, Assembly Language

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Committee member of Kingswood Science Society (2014 - 2016)

Member of Rotaract Club in University of Peradeniya (2018 - 2021)

Member of Kingswood Information Technology Society (2012 - 2016)

Member of Kingswood Chess Team (2008 - 2012)

Member of Kingswood Baseball Team who were the 2nd Runners Up at All Island School Baseball Tournament 2008 (2008 - 2009)

Special Award for Baseball at Kingswood Colours Night 2009

REFERENCES

Prof. G.M.I.R. Godaliyadda Prof. Vijitha R. Herath

Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Electrical and Electronic Engineering cal and Electronic Engineering University of Peradeniya roshangodaliyadda777@gmail.com vijitha@eng.pdn.ac.lk +94 77 770 9035

Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Electri-University of Peradeniya +94716732688

Prof. M.P.B. Ekanayake

Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Electrical and Electronic Engineering University of Peradeniya mpb.ekanavake@gmail.com +94773648882